{
    "id": "0f96461a3f004bbcbd1f392a2f7f81ad",
    "title": "Reported Speech Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "James said that he ………………….. his friends for dinner.",
            "description": "James said, 'I have invited my friends.' Present perfect in the direct speech becomes past perfect in the indirect speech.",
            "answers": [
                "invited",
                "has invited",
                "had invited"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Stella said that she ……………………….. her friends.",
            "description": "Will in direct speech becomes would in indirect speech.",
            "answers": [
                "will also call",
                "would also call"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "They wondered what they ………………………… for dinner.",
            "description": "Will in direct speech becomes would in indirect speech.",
            "answers": [
                "will serve",
                "would serve"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Mother asked what I ……………………….. in my room.",
            "description": "'What are you doing in your room?' asked mother. Present continuous tense in direct speech becomes past continuous in indirect speech.",
            "answers": [
                "am doing",
                "was doing",
                "have been doing"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I warned him ……………………………. careful.",
            "description": "'Be careful,' I told him. I warned him to be careful. We use to-infinitives to report imperatives. ",
            "answers": [
                "to be",
                "being"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "She cried that there …………………………. a cockroach on her table.",
            "description": "'There is a cockroach on my table,' she cried. Is in the direct speech becomes was in the indirect speech.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "was",
                "were"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She replied that she ……………………….",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "is reading",
                "was reading",
                "has been reading"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She asked me if she ………………………… a message with me.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "can leave",
                "could leave",
                "will leave"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The child said that she ………………………. afraid.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "was",
                "has been"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The doctor recommended that I ……………………………… increase my intake of fruits and vegetables.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "will",
                "would",
                "should"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "She cried that she …………………………..",
            "description": "'I have been duped,' she cried. / She cried that she had been duped. ",
            "answers": [
                "is duped",
                "has been duped",
                "had been duped"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "They told him ………………………….. off.",
            "description": "'Be off,' they told him. They told him to off. We use to-infinitives to report imperatives. ",
            "answers": [
                "that he be",
                "to be"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}